The truth is relative.
My Winnipeg is a documentary, drama, comedy film directed by Guy Maddin.
The geographical dead center of North America and the beloved birthplace of Guy
Maddin, Winnipeg, is the frosty and mysterious star of Maddin’s film.
Fact, fantasy and memory are woven seamlessly together in this work,
conjuring a city as delightful as it is fearsome.
Mother, played by Ann Savage.
Janet Maddin, played by Amy Stewart.
Guy Maddin, played by Darcy Fehr.
Mayor Cornish, played by Louis Negin.
Cameron Maddin, played by Brendan Cade.
Ross Maddin, played by Wesley Cade.
My Winnipeg is a 2007 Canadian film directed and written by
Guy Maddin with dialogue by George Toles.
Described by Maddin as a "docu-fantasia", that melds "personal history, civic tragedy, and mystical
hypothesizing", the film is a surrealist mockumentary about Winnipeg, Maddin's home town.
A New York Times article described the film's unconventional take on the documentary style by noting that it
"skates along an icy edge between dreams and lucidity, fact and fiction, cinema and psychotherapy".
My Winnipeg began when Maddin was commissioned by the Documentary
Channel, and originally titled Love Me, Love My Winnipeg.
Maddin's producer told him "Don't give me the frozen hellhole everyone knows that Winnipeg is" so Maddin cast Darcy Fehr in the role of "Guy
Maddin" and structured the documentary around a metafictional plot that mythologizes the city and Maddin's autobiography.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.